...appearing...build the session is what can...do for android
and ios so obviously here I'm going to tell you about what a measure can do if
you're building android ios apps how it can help you built better applications if you already what's the
keynote which if you have an I'll just go back and watch that there were some really cool announcements
that have to do with android ios coding and
...I'm not going to dive into those but I will be focusing on as your...today the first
...a little bit about me you haven't caught me on cloud cover or another
them before my name is chris reiner I'm a senior technical
ranges that microsoft I focused primarily on open-source and?
Maybe...of technology as far as how we can use that along with
leisure I do a lot of android ios development obviously that's why I'm here talks you...if you
...twitter you might be...picture that's my job and then also, you know,
I'm really into sailing that's kind of idea when I'm not doing stuff like
...started by going over a can be agenda for the session
...is to a quick overview of as you're just kind of a high-level view of what it
is education...familiar with it and...going to focus on two different things making more powerful
...so services...can help you build better applications and then
...testing...so services that can help you build-out your applications
...that's building them touching them running...
And, then we'll kind of replicas to quick summary
and provide a few ways to contact both myself and some of the teams that work on
...relative to what...talking about today.
So, first for an overview you know, really popular thing that you'll hear from you probably heard
...the build sessions is that microsoft is really becoming
a mobile first cloud first company and it's really more the microsoft of world
...people are doing more things on their phones first before they look anywhere else and people
...at the cloud is...other problems so instead of getting other traditional computer, you know,
maybe they're...mobile...tablet instead of having a set
...your own datacenter by your own service people are looking at the cloud and we're really embracing that and, you know,
this specific session is really all about that because we're really talking about how we can use the
clouded to build better mobile applications so microsoft as your as microsoft's
cloud platform and that's a kind of a nebulous term for a lot of different
services and offerings that microsoft provides for application developers and these
...developers building out, you know, I web applications so something like you know,
and, instagram perhaps something like that just a big what website all the way down to, you know,
just small, you know, just my own little personal website sort of stuff and then this could be also stuff for
people building mobile applications ...willing, you know,
big server farm etc just tons of different things we're going
...highlighting some of the services that you see here on this graph
...have specifically to do with a mobile and more specifically to do with...
and right so we'll go through all these things right here but there's a ton of stuff in here whether it's
a virtual machines and infrastructures service or website which is
...service to database storage options to
of education a lot of these things are software...coined use from mobile
...do in a pretty simple easy way so what comes to mobile measure we look at
kind of three different things we want to make sure the suffer buildings accessible is open
...easy without accessibility obviously
...android hugely insanely popular devices so when we build-out services we want-to make sure
these services can work with these operating systems we talk about open
we mean that we...make sure you understand how things work and what's going on so lot of the
...we're going to use around look at say...
open-source on get so if you want understand how things work under the hood you
can look at that sdk if you want to make a...request you can do that we except
...requests or very open about how us technology works and then easy.
It's all great if, you know,
you can use it on the different platforms and you can see how orson...is easy-to-use it's going
to be really hard to make sense of why you would even bother so the
...see today it's really easy to get plugged into both your ios
...applications
let's go ahead and jump right into talking about making more powerful apps.
So, first...going to talk about is as your mobile services and
...something we've been talking about for a couple years now and it's really quite
...a offers a lot of capabilities essentially this is a platforms
...service offering from microsoft measure that contains functionality to
do the three big things are data storage authentication and push
...when it comes...storage by default kind of the
...out-of-the-box screens you get is it's going to store data in a sql database was really nice
about mobile services is that the sequel database that uses is not something that,
you know, hidden behind the scenes you can access...can your data unless you're using mobile
services is a normal...error sequel database so
if you decide you want to take all your data out of that and put you...system you can do that if you need to
connect that database and do more enhance database administration you can do that
we also have a mobile services...that you can pretty easily connected to other data stores so if you
...something like a no sequel system like table storage...db you
could do that if you need to connect into a sas provider like sales
force dynamics you can do that a lot of functionality you get out of
that data storage as far as user authentication goes this is a great feature that
enables you to really easily giver uses the ability to login so that you can
then know who they are and make sure...only getting the data that they're authorized to see
...mobile services has connectivity to do authentication with facebook
twitter microsoft accounts goo hunt and then also as
you're active directory we'll talk more about the adjective directory a little bit waiter
because it extends beyond just what mobile services can do and then another
...here is push notifications push locations are hugely important when you building
mobile applications the vast majority of mobile applications are using these push notations whether
it's something where you're popping up something to the user or descending information down...the application to create
a very seamless very enticing experience as far as push
...go with measure mobile services their support for aps which supports ios and
...austen their support for android for both
...google android so gc...
group messaging amazon android so amazon device messaging as well as by
...windows, windows phone emptiness w...this of works ...you
...the amazon...provocations and, then were also working on some other enhance of
for...messaging as well now behind-the-scenes you're able to actually
do your coding so build your own logic out
b dot net for...js as well some other languages?
And,...client-side their st case for all the upping
systems you'd expect so for ios for android for windows,
windows phone and there's also suffer cross...solution so if you building is amr
application or phone gap application you can use those sdk you can
...inside of those applications...is a very can, you know, compelling or,
you know, an encompassing offer if you're building locations so you don't have to worry about building
out this back or how do you handle...off of education or how do you
...aps re-do push...mobile services does this for you and this is also
if you could build yourself but it's going
to take time and you're going to have to be able to test it and
...going to be reliable and it's going to work and that will scale out mobile services here and does all this
for you already let's go ahead and look at mobile service really quickly?
So, here we are in the microsoft error portal if I wanted this is the current portal we're
...be going between this and the preview portal throughout the session if we wanted to
create a new mobile service we could just go...create and then we give it a name we choose
...create a new database using existing one...us subscription we want to put it
...where we want as far as around the world goes I've already...mobile service
...skip past that and go into build mobile service demo the first thing you see is the quick
start page where you can choose a platform you want to start with and it'll give you a guide for either
creating new application or connecting existing
...just downloading the sdk I've already done this and I've already got in iowa's and
...application...going to walk through and we'll kind of look through some of the portal and, you know,
instead of going through the whole creation process will just focus on
...already created so this is going to be this simple to do application you get out of the
...just with a few modification to it...I'll point out as they already have a to
do item table to store my data so if I go over to.
Android studio I've got this build mobile services application here and the first we'll do is
...just run and walk through some of the code so it's going to go ahead and assembler application.
And,...on our emulator.
And, then we'll go over here to our emulator and just a moment we should see our application run.
casing to launch up the first thing we're going to see is it's going to prompt us to authenticate I've already
added authentication in my application so here we've got doing twitter off so I'm
going-to go ahead and type in my username and then I will take
this off-screen type in my password.
And, we'll go ahead and sign-in.
And, some login it shows me my id it's twitter...
a big number was really great is that now the client-side application has
an id from...user and then my back-end also
has id from user so now I can actually start saving data
...that user doing queries off the user id and that's how you go ahead and
you restrict access to data so-if, for example, I save...to do item.
So, we'll say we're going to talk about mobile services when I say this data on the back-end if I wanted
to I could add the id to this data object and then I know that this
to item was saved by me the user and then whenever I get my to do
...refresh the...I can make sure that on the only once iness.
So, let's just had a couple more should
you items from android so to from
...let's go ahead and that now if we go back to the portal.
And, we go into this you...table we'll see that we've got some data here
...gives...you know,
what dns across being, you know, the text...a complete field mobile services you something called
dynamics immunization so that it will generate database
comes and the scheme is...for you
sequentially application and let's go ahead and look at some of the code?
Most...codes going-to-take place in the to do activity this is kind of...if you hefner with android this is
that you know, essentially the thing that represents the page we're looking at really so first we
...service client is part of the sdk
that or referencing this mobile service clients...kind of...our initial access into
our application whenever mobile service table this is what we use with the to
do am object right here this has this room has the different point
of different properties that we have is part of that and id a text
...complete field now if we go back in here and we look at the on create
method personal see is this mobile service client instantiated worry...url
...mobile service and an application key this application key is a unique...for
...mobile service and what this allows me to do is I can
set security settings on the different tables differ methods part of
...service whether not they requires application key come across a header when I
criminal service client like this it's going to automatically send this as a header with
...request so next thing I do after a create a
is I call authenticate in this case if I go to authenticate and
if you looked at the mobile...sdk for android before you might think this looks a little bit
different because we're using this stuff called futures and work
creating call backs essentially in order to better facilitation functionality down the road we
kind of changed how it works it still looks relatively similar just a little bit nomenclature,
nomenclature changes so inside here
we're calling login on the client object or passing in the twitter provider if we
...to do google microsoft etc we could just change that
right here?
Then inside of that we pass a call back which says that when we successfully
login go ahead and create that papa says hey your login and then call create table
create table is what is does the for code to say hey when I
ever I use this m to do table object this is the classes...I'm using its the to do
entail behind-the-scenes then we're calling refresh items on the to do table and if we look at
...here were calling you...we see...here we see in a...
task that's running and basically saying go fetch the data where the complete...equal
false so if we go back to replication...we just mark this as complete now
free refresh that commands...this time it only pullback one because we
have a completed item and then after that we just add to the adapter which is basically just normal list
view functionality then we actually want to add new item.
We create instance of the to item class we set the text and complete flag and then we
And, to do table dot insert...the item in really,
really simple functionality for talking back to this mobile service and
very android specific just a second what it looks like
...ios and it's going to be a little bit different because it's going to be appropriate for
...see developer one of the things I want to show off is this build a
...file and if we look in here.
This build...if you look in here we'll see that we are referencing this
measure mobile services sdk this
...beta now this is actually in a repository so we don't have
to pull down a jar filing...that is part of the greater build...automatic in a
...in the of library the code for mobile services let's go ahead and
hop overlook this and ios.
So, here I have a very similar application that I'll go ahead and run.
And, there we have the...similar...so first thing we'll do is...login here as well different,
different application running on different advice media login again.
So, we'll...password here.
we see that we have similar data here I've still got some data...the last
...but if I say from ios can add
...item and now if we go back to our entered application
we refresher we see that we get the data so now doesn't matter which device we save the
data...the other device can see that data so looking at our objective
see application person we see is here in object to see we've added a windows
measure mobile services framework this is just like how in the a
...replication we compile the jar from the repository or we pulled that infinite
...up here we actually at a framework now inside here we've got this to
do service class and this can have some similar code or similar objects at least
...an microsoft client again that's the entry point...service then we've got a add a method complete a
sinking data so if we go to...service quest here.
We look at the creation we see same build mobile service director
national dot net url and the exact same application key again that has
do security will look at the...just a second so there's some stuff in here that we're not going look
at to deeply but basically the ios sdk
is prebuilt to store data locally using core data and
sql white I'll talk more about that when it comes to offline data
...in a few minutes but down here we create a...table with its url name when it comes
adding and item we pass ns dictionary the item and look at the code
...just a second we've hassan or recall insert on-scene table and
...and that item so very similar we had nearer recall insert on the table object
...item we call update on the same...table and we want to
...the data down we call...data and pull data is basically creating a query
or also do items, you know, it it's creating query with the to answer...for
the complete flag as equal false now if we go ahead and look at the to use you
...kind of...portion of if you're not familiar with
ios development for go down here to where we first login here
we're calling login you control provider on the client this is a way of generating a
view that wraps that web login that we did against twitter we've
...twitter here just like before if we wanted to pass...else like
...microsoft account tool...facebook we could and then when we get
...we've authenticate...we cover fresh now when we actually
...an item?
Or I'm sorry we...fetch the data this is what's happening here we're saying hey we want
...the to do am data with complete...equal
now just like we did in java just a little bit more specific to of doing...c.
And, then when we actually go to adding item?
Here we just create as dictionary so basically achy value
...set we...into the ad item...energy service and again behind-the-scenes that's
...insert...table.
So, a little bit different code...you know,
definitely different syntax wise but it's doing the exact same thing as what we did in our
android application let's go look at the portal and look at a few different things first thing
we'll look at is the script calm I don't have any additional
functionality in here right now except for once this loads.
We'll see that I m logging data and will look at isn't just a second essential I'm doing is whenever
...certain item I'm logging the user object and this contains the user...
users id and what's really great about the scripts...is where I can put added functionality so if I wanted
to data validation like make sure the...you item was only a few characters long I could put
in right here if I wanted to check and make sure the user id was valid I could do that here
though I know that since this...through the user id is valid but I could do any sort of checks
...logic here with it...third-party service maybe I want to...twitter anything amounted...
doing here now I mention mobile services academic optimization you can also if you want to add
columns from here as well as remove columns as well?
Then ...security and essentially by default the security level on mobile services
is that as long as the application key comes over as a header the request goes through but you
can change that to three other settings everyone allows you to basically just as long as,
you know, the url you're able to make the request only authenticate uses means that user object has to be
for an valid and mobile services going to make sure that user visibility and for-you
...only scripps and admins is another way of locking it down so that only other
scripts can access the table or someone...send a master key which is an additional
...somewhat like the...key over your service.
...mobile services has custom api
as where basically when you make request against the table...using a rest...
generated for-you with custom api as you can create a new api specify permissions just
like we did before and you can define whatever functionality is not...do an actual table.
The scheduler allows you to create schedule jobs that can either run on a schedule whether
it every few minutes every few hours every day or on-demand so just one
off and when you create one of these...able to add the same kind of script that we did we looked at the
...second ago where you can programmer functionality one so maybe you want to clean-up all data maybe want to
...regular push notification any that functionality can be put in here pusher applications is something interesting
push applications actually powered by another service that's part of measure called notification
...we're going to look at
...in more detail in a few minutes but suffice to say mobile services has
really easy connectivity into push locations where you just need to set up your
...here credentials to the...and then you can register from the device using
...mobile services sdk no identity's where you put any of the settings for the eight-eighty providers you want to
use so right now I've got twittering here and I've got google in here and this is what
allows me to use the twitter authentication because if I tried to use twitter authentication without
...settings and it wouldn't work same time like if I tried facebook right now
wouldn't work and the way you get the settings as you go through the twitter developer...the facebook...
and you create...application there and essentially you get them url your mobile service and then they give you back
information so you can set up authentication the last couple tabs
first to get configured this allows us to change what sequel database or sequel server one reference the
scripps behind our table access...custom api...scheduler there are
available in a very get repository so you can pull those so scripts down locally
make changes and push them up and...deploy them on your mobile service you can turn
that dynamic immunization on and off I'll talk more about hyper...but later for
crosswords and resource sharing this allows you to basically using ishmael javascript library to
access mobile services and in that case in order to make that cross domain javascript
request you need to put the domain you're coming from into this system there's some developer
analytic systems you can use and then there's a few different settings and monitoring things as far as
scale goes right now is mobile service will be in the free mode?
Like many of...other office manager there's a free mode that lets you play
around develop essentially perpetually without having to worry about paying
a price that's not true freshly but there's no we're not charging fourth.
Those are limited though as far as what you can you know-how how much you can use how many
requests you can make once you go to basic standard you're then able to scale-up the
number of units or how many request you're going to make a month and you can also do auto scale and
...by the number api...not paying for more than you want to
...the free and now look at the...now I showed you before that when I
...to do item on actually logging the user id the
user object so in here we see a
logarithm log entry for the user object and we see that, you know,
my levels authenticated on authenticated user got my twitter id here and if I wanted to I
...the identity's and get more information from twitter so
that's mobile services a lot of functionality makes it will really powerful
of applications without having to worry about how all of this back-end stuff really works underneath the covers?
Now imagine...we look at the issa but part
of mobile services is a feature called offline datacenter
now this is something that's primarily a client-side feature allows you to do is instead of just
send your data directly appear mobile service you can send it to a local table which is powered by
sequel lie in the ios instance it's using...data on top of
...it but then you can...that data again
...mobile service what this means is that if your device goes offline you can still make
your application work it will just write the changes locally and then once you get back online you can
push the changes or...changes with your server now right now the client
sdk for dot net ios republic the anyone's currently in beta so
...you can use it can work...just isn't production...again all of these using
sequel at behind-the-scenes now that...is developer control...can dictate when you want to
...so maybe you don't want to think a lot of data if they're just on their...connection but if they're on their
wife I connection you do you...behind-the-scenes on the server-side it uses
...optimistic concurrency essentially what this means is the
first-rate wins so if I have two different applications maybe one running online
...device one running on my android device and I m offline both and I make changes
of the same data...device pushes the...data first my
...connection tries to put the data...as hey you don't have...data you're trying
...update you need to solve this problem and when you get that sort of conflict you can have the on
the server-side
on the client so if you just want to...the data you could just do that on the server-side but if you want
...user and say hey this is the actual data its current you sure you want to save your data you
can do that on the client-side now as your mobile services been around for a couple years and
its focus was really on building mobile applications but...a few other services that are part of
...that are really useful in conjunction with mobile services so there's actual website which allow
you deploy web applications whether dot net java php
...js or other languages and this has a lot of really cool functionality like you can
do us site sought so you can say I want to test I want to test
the environment production environment you can do automated backup and restoring
at you can do a lot of...really cool functionality but even though mobile
services is kind of built off of...websites you couldn't use the same functionality from
measure websites and you couldn't hosting a web application inside your mobile service that was, you know,
for your mobile application you get the host that separately inside of...website now additionally
their services some called based talk services which allow you to increase functionality
for mobile applications as well such as connecting from a mobile application
...on premise database or web service now we just recently
...measure...service and this essentially combines this functionality
altogether in addition to some other functionality so as you rhappe service your now
able to build web apps and mobile apps and logic apps
and api apps and really right now what we really focus on is this web apps
and mobile apps because the mobile apps essentially the future of mobile services so of
functionally mobile services is right there in mobile apps but additionally you're able to deploy is
kind of a bigger piece other pieces of the application so the same...employer mobile apps
you can employer web apps too and it's basically one application...
Worrying about what's going on over here in...website much going over the on over there
...mobile in your mobile service it's all one app service.
Some of the new capabilities for mobile apps that we, you know,...with edge websites better now
capable of being use from mobile applications include long-running task for web job or web jobs
...with...a bit bucket via so
otto load balancing out of scaling as well as geographical
disaster recovery virtual network networking hybrid connections and that sleight
...deployments I...and this is currently in preview so if you're
billion production application should...mobile services but down-arrow when this goes to
...a...general the ability this
...be the future of mobile connectivity when it comes to measure let's
take a look at just how we would set-up and...service and what it looks like?
In order to do this we're going to actually go to the preview portal inside
here we can go in and I can create a new mobile application
and inside here it's going to ask me for...different information like where I want to be what I want
to be called stuff like that.
...skip has this...going to go into a mobile application...already created.
And, inside here we can see I can add a clients again this is just
...previews...all the clients are here so where we saw all the android ios
...and phone...windows, windows phone before we only see a few of them here
and preview we can go into the different
authentication options as far as uses that can access this and what they can do with it we can
go into the settings in see the different user authentication and other
options and things like that we can use...we can see...push
...services essentially like I said before all the functionality that was there before
in our in our mobile services going-to be here...of the other things I'll show you
in highway is that when you grab an applications, for example, the ios
app you can you download not just the ios application but also
a server-side so the deployment model here's a little bit different whereas with this mobile service
we're doing everything in the portal here for the visuals for the dot net piece you
...visual studio solution...deploy that for your mobile app now again this is a previous
we don't have a node version yet but is going-to be coming down the road?
...go ahead and...back to our slides.
...was I was notification...facilitate manage
push notifications and this works like I said before with android ios windows and windows phone
and several varieties of and representations of works with now I'm going to show you this for both of
...but some of the features that notification has laid...for you is targeted portion applications so-if you
want-to push to curses phone, for example, you...that or if you want to
push to everybody that build you could do that and a facilitates doing across platforms
so pushed above android and ios and windows...windows phone really easily using temples
...the great things about...is highly scalable so if you need to deliver millions...locations you're going
to be able to do so let's go ahead and look at notification...
First thing we'll do is we'll go back to the portal and now I'm going to service
bus which is what...a part of an...of
...already created call build mobile apps hub now inside
Similarly sony before how we configure are ...for mobile services again it's using
location of behind-the-scenes but if I go into configure for...of this is where I can
set my windows...settings my apple aps
...muhammad's settings I've already uploaded certificate and
set-up gcm if I wanted to if I was just
...gcm for the first-time I would go into an application google oper
...I go to api is I'd turn on a google
...messaging
...friend right there and then you just grab a server key which is how
my notification of can authenticate talked into a google developed google developer
...so I've already got the setup from a client-side
attributes information I need then are the name of my hub and then the listen shared access
injure so I can actually register with the hub so then let's go ahead and look at this on an android application?
So, let's first run...application.
And,...run this on emulator.
And, this can be really simple application...going to
allow us to do is register with our notification hub and then get
...so what that...the background abner
ok so here we are so we see we haven't registered yet of your button original gcm...got a few different
...location...personal do it registered gcm this goes through my
application it basically uses the google how...which is part of google's android api
as it goes up to gc...it says I want to register and passes in a
...id which is another...get from the google developer
consul so when I hit that I get back this really long string which identifies my
...my device to gc and now after that what I can do is I'm going
to use this notification have object create using the hub name and
...string I mentioned before and I'm going to call this register method I just
passion the registration the registration id so register to with no tags now what I'm going
to do next is I'm going to go into a different mobile services which I set up to help me do some push
notifications so I've got some custom api
in here that I can just access via the web and the first we're going to look at is just
...push to gcm and aps.
So, if we go and look at this script right here
we'll see that I've got the hub name again and I've got a different connection...this one has for shared
...is a full access signature so that means I can actually not just register but I can actually trigger
provocations so then down here I'm using the location of service...aps dot send
and passing in a payload for that...doing gcm...passing...for
that now let's go ahead and refresh this page right here and if we return or application.
We see hello for measure and if I look up here I can see that I've got a portion of creation
showing up now the next thing I want to do is I want to actually run this
and ios so I've got a similar application...and ios.
much like before...creating notification up with the name and the string
time registering with aps that's going on behind the scenes of getting back a string and then
I'm registering without with a advice token underpass
...token...let's go ahead and run this application and I'm
going-to go ahead and screen share so we can actually see this running.
And, there we go so now return the application we've already
...token back or register with no tags.
Now what I want to do is I'm...go over here I'm in a refresh.
I'm actually going to get my emulator is race we can watch them
on a refresh.
And, we can see looked...the both places we see it from ios
we see it through on android let's go ahead and go back to the code...never look at these register with tags
method what this allows us to do is when we do the registration we can say I want you
...information to minute-to-minute registration so in this case here I've
got bill of android user I've got all users and I'm using just...
registration id in...strings figured ios we'll see we've got a very similar thing we have...
ray of strings we...and registered native device...we do that the token data and then
our tag set so now if I go back to my to applications.
We register with tags from our ios app and we'll go to
...application and will...tags?
Now we'll go back up to the portal...got a different method here
called push test tag and this is going to be very similar except now the first parameter to
sand is build in this case an android user in this case so
I'm saying when I say aps...and build it's going to look for any tag...registered with
...build any registration that's got that build tag is going to try to push
that and then when I do gc m is going to say hey anybody's richer within
...user push to them so let's go ahead and here go through our website
...test tag and if we look here we can see we've got?
Hello, build and then we got that push invocation on android as well and we can look
about if we just go right here so hello end-users so now I can target
...locations for one specific device or another
specific device now so far I've had to do both push
...for gcm in aps separately that's
really not ideal I don't want to have to have separate blocks of code anywhere I want to
push location to handle each provider what I can do instead is when I...put with by notification of a
...a template and this template can dictate what format I should receive
...location so if we look at this template for android.
We see I've got this data message and then this dollar sign message right here
and what happens is whenever I send a message parameter or message field as a
portion of vacation to attempted push notification...deal with a pulling...the right
recipients base...the tags...getting the format the data in the right format to push to,
for example, in this case gc...if we look over at the ap and
sone or the ios one we'll see it's a little bit different but it's got that aps and the same
dollar sign message so this is the...format for aps
...gcm but that's of course because when I get a push this ios application it should be using
gi aps so I'll...register attempts on both my devices here?
And, now we'll go back to the poorer and I go to this push...template page and
inside here I'm creating a payload where I've got this message job this message parameter
...template pushed everyone and then I call notification of service dot
send so don't send to other...aps just send anyone that applies to
I'm not sending a tag here but I could if I wanted to and then just...the payload so now we'll say push
...template.
And, if we go back to our...device we see we got that portion of we...device it
was too fast we see right here and see if we can refresher really quickly and then see
...push everyone we gotta get ios as well so really powerful way to get
push notifications regardless of what type of application or what operations
...additionally regardless of whether you're using as your
...data storage or use replication anything else you can just use the service just
...you portion locations like I'm doing here and in addition to having
client service decays that work with android ios and windows,
windows phone from the back-end...a lot of ways of talking to unification of to actually trigger
push notifications you can use a dot net
...talks...you can use a
note sdk which is essentially what I'm doing right here I'm using this
...javascript ck there's also a java sdk and then everything is actually expose
via...the rest api so if you're building a application
...that you want to talk unification hubs with but you don't have
...sdk for you can just use the rest api and it's very easy let's head back to slides?
So, if you feature...services will talk about that we won't show and real detail
...the first one is as your storage now so far when I showed you mobile services we
...sequel database behind-the-scenes...data I mention this is just,
you know, built...services you can change if you want as your
...facilitates a few different kinds of storage including
no sequel via table storage files
...large data via blobs and then the messages and descriptions via
...now there's an error ack available for the
so-if you need to talk directly to the storage systems from...application you can do and I always
...progress...interested in that you should get in touch with us.
I mention authentication earlier and I
talk about how you could use as your eccentric free-form mobile services now address directory
is a system that stands on its own known for authentication and what's great about address
directory is that there's an edge...active directory authentication library for ios
for android for all these others operating systems that you can use to authenticate
users again regardless of whether...using another...you know,
within measure and...going...can...this with your on premise
actual directory so if you want your employees to log in with their
corporate credentials before they can access some sort of service or some sort of application you can use the
address directory library to make sure that happens this uses industry-standard secure
off to enables you access api is like office and sharepoint without having to prompt
...every time and like I mentioned before it's...with on premise you can make it think
...privacy officer's sixty-five is office in the cloud and there's a
library that allows you to...your sharepoint online files unless
you're outlook mail calendars and context as well as your as your
actual directory craft and...works with the ad l so essentially you can use the ado library
...finicky users...start making calls using the office fifty-five
st case media services is a really cool service
...you do video-on-demand so from administration perspective you can ingest new
media you-can...you can package it and you can also delivered
down to applications now it's really quite easy to get this to watches on both mobile or
web and there's different authentication options whether you need you
...around so think that you want to be able to distribute media
...that nobody can duplicate up to, you know,
just secure media...make sure gets there securely but once it's there you're less concern.
...talk about really quickly is biz talk
...services hybrid connections...is going to be part of...what that...that
...service but for right now you can so user mobile services as well as hybrid connections
...this allows you to do is points a endpoint within ager...
endpoint within your enterprise using a hybrid connection manager so whereas by default
mobile services using a sequel database inside of editor you can use a hybrid connection to point
...database running your own datacenter and then mobile services will basically automatically
funnel all traffic to this hybrid connection so...all the data is only being stored in your
database on your in your datacenter as opposed to measure you can use the same thing to talk to, you know,
internal services whether they...services or any other endpoint you might want to the next section we'll talk about
is building in testing apps so if you're building
an application what else can...measure to help you do that.
First...talk about is android plugins and we have these for...studio and intelligent
these allow you really easy way to connects to measure mobile services on whether that's to connect
...existing or create anyone notification hubs as well as your service and office
sixty-five activities including selling permissions let's take a really quick look at the android
studio plug-in so just go back to android studio and I'm just going to go to
my application I'll go to new and then I'll go down to microsoft and I can
choose as your service directory and...basically allow me, you know, create a activity which
...the functionality of talking the
...service or notifications or both if I go back and I say new
...can go to.
Microsoft office sixty-five activity and it lets me...
attributed again can dictate whether I want to talk to outlook services the file services or share
pointless another little bit functionality inside the plug-in is you're actually able to go
in...mobile services your virtual machines and your storage can't connect to those as
...nuance.
And, you'll see added function...this
amazon so visual studio online is a really cool tool it's not
really it's not essentially visual studio the id online but what it
...is it's project management but it's really enhance at the base what you get out of is you can
do version control and you can...this up with get or tiff and
it's free for five people you can also do more actual project management
...create bugs you can create...you contract work items all that stuff and then some
really cool functionality is stuff that we previewed last october last november and it
allows you to build applications in a continuous integration for android and ios and
this includes running your test as well as publishing compile apps let's take a quick look at some of the stuff that will have
coming there so if I go back to the browser so this is...online if I want to
create a new project I could do so really easily...just give it mining
say build project and then I can choose what process temple if you want
to do that and then we can choose between team foundation server version control or get now there's nothing
we're about this is traditional get so once you create this get repository you can use the command line
...pushing and pulling your code into visual sphere online I've already creator...
the contains all the code samples I showed you today now we could go in here we
...look at the code if we wanted to but let's go to this
build previewing and again this is functionality will have coming down the road what is
...preview right now so what I could do right here is I can create a new
...definition I'll just say it's an empty definition notice we have a few
...templates already for visual studios...in x code and then once I create definition I can go to
add build steps like android build so build my...replication or sign
my ap...I could go down here...x code build
an x code package ios soap to actually build the ip a which really cool this is,
you know,
I've got several different projects in here so I could have several build steps...sever build definitions and I could just point
...you know, where's my build by my...wrapper which project director my using should I run the
...emulator do I run...tests and then here I can actually say I want you to sign
...creating ack so this create some really cool functionality where you
can basically automate building your application running test and...so think of,
you know, you're...you're testing your application now in your in your enterprise
...company and every time you make a code change you want to make a new ack available
for your testers this can do that you can build this application every time...change it
...test you can create a new...and assigning step and then you...you know, a scripted
...that will take that...you know, maybe email to users or delivered to wherever it needs to be so that
they can start...same goes for ex code...really interesting because
we can exactly right now build-out iowa's application online but you can
...a visionary online...a...so ios ten machine,
for example, and, build that rx code application that way and then you have that same
...to packers that up and then delivers somewhere if you want to really very powerful stuff
for to continues integration building...your applications.
App insight provide easy application monitoring and this essentially
...performance modeling of your application you contract usage and metrics you-can review
...crashes information there...it back and...so let's say you're doing them
that mobile measure...service and you've got an application and you...a mobile or website for
the application well you can use this adj or app insights to get information on the
usage of your mobile app as well as your website let's take a quick look at what
this looks like now I've already added some code into this standard application to do
...insights person you see is I just added this compile directive...migrate
...file so it's going to go out and pull down the...insights library which is available get herb like all the other sdk
...today and then in my...activity or let's go back to the manifest first
and I manifest here I'm specifying information instrumentation key which I get out of the portal and
...look...second...do activity in on...
...down at the bottom here I'm creating an instance of my telemetry
client coin track events and saying...if I say trick event of...and
I'm also doing it when I have an item added since I did this stuff earlier in my application if
you go to the proto we should see some events that have been logged so we'll go back here the portal
...go and return to home.
Algorithm build mobile app insights now if we look in here we should see we already have a
few events logged after...so we see we've got events log my happened crash for
me crested here but I can see that I started the at five times I added one item and
out-dated one item I can see where the requests were made from
...I can go to the metrics explorer and look at
additional information after I can figure it so what sort of metrics to I want to get a lot
of options there if I go down here we can see, you know, what version of the android sdk
...be use in this case is built for ex eighty-six is five-point-one that's my screen
...tons...really great information here as far as getting
...goes if we go to you know, the contrary explains what you...get started
...and if I go to settings this is where I can grab that instrumentation key that I put
inside my application so like I said really easy goes up and running and
you start getting really great information about the usage of your application...in rate
it works and ios as well as all sorts of other devices going back to our slides?
Now visual...online is...online...looked at where we its source control we can build
that build-out a project...project management visual studio itself has
some functionality if you are building android ios applications so
...connectivity into cordova...samurai
...doing cplus-plus build and deployment debugging
and there's also an android emulator that runs as part of visual studio to help you better and,
test out and run your applications so to summarize we looked at today as you can
our...back and no matter what your building as far as
modification goes so as your mobile services which is production approve right now
there's address service and mobile apps which is in preview right now and it's kind of the future
where we're going there's notification helps channel push locations and
networks with mobile app mobile services but can also work as a stain on if you just need to do push notifications
there's answer storage measure active directory is...hybrid services for making more powerful
inching applications as far as helping you build better applications...visual
...online there's those pieces...studio there's app insights and those id
...looked at thank you for turning in washes I hope you had a great time
and build if you want to reach out to me you can always do so on twitter chris for eisner you
can retest...my website crystallized dot com and then if you feedback on mobile apps
or services you-can email mobile services microsoft-dot-com and then we always welcome feedback and
user requests at feedback...ager dot com thanks everyone and have a great day?